SANDIP THAPA

Tinthana-14, Chandragiri, Bagmati Province, Nepal sandipthapa386@gmail.com (+977) 9808976977

A highly motivated and hard-working individual, graduate of Computer Science with about 2 years of active participation on web development using React.js & Next.js. Wide range of technical skill-set and attention to detail. Loves to work as a Frontend Developer where I could create digital magic and elevate user interface and experience to the next level.

EXPERIENCE

JAN 2022 - PRESENT

JR. FRONTEND DEVELOPER, CAGTU NEPAL PVT. LTD.

- Convert Figma designs into web pages using HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Develop new user-facing features using React.js and Next.js with Typescript.
- Develop and maintain fast, bug-free, and re-usable components for the in-house product.
- Collaborate with design team to enhance user interfaces and its experience.
- Implement and manage version controlling of the project using git flow.

SEPT 2021 - DEC 2021

FRONTEND DEVELOPER - INTERNSHIP, EKBANA SOLUTIONS PTE. LTD.

- Developed supermarket app with React.js.
- API integration and data handling using Context API.
- Got to learn about Software Development Life Cycle using SCRUM.

EDUCATION

2018 - 2021

BSc (Hons) IT, HERALD COLLEGE, UNIVERSITY OF WOLVERHAMPTON

- Introduced to fundamentals of programming.
- Introduced to Data Structure and Algorithms.
- Introduced to Database Management Systems.
- Assigned to multiple mini and group projects.
- Worked on different research, communication and collaboration skills.

2016 - 2018

INTERMEDIATE - SCIENCE, KATHMANDU BERNHARDT COLLEGE

Majors: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Computer Science

PROJECTS

JUN 2022 - PRESENT

Homaale, Associated with CAGTU NEPAL PVT. LTD.

Technologies: Next.js, Typescript, Redux, Styled-components, Mantine, Axios, Formik, React Query, Google Maps, Docker

<u>View Project</u> ☐

JUL 2023

ExerGym - Gym exercise app

Technologies: React.js, Material UI, Tailwind CSS, Rapid API (ExerciseDB)

View Project 2

APR 2022 - JUN 2022

Car Hub - Car showcase app

Technologies: Next.js(SSR), Typescript, Tailwind CSS, Rapid API (Cars by API-Ninjas)

View Project

APR 2022 - JUN 2022

Cagtu Nepal, Associated with CAGTU NEPAL PVT. LTD.

Technologies: Next.js(SSG, ISR), Typescript, SCSS, Docker

View Project 2

KEY SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3/SCSS/Tailwind CSS
- Bootstrap5
- Javascript TypeScript
- React.js
- Next.js
- React Query
- Mantine UI
 - Formik Yup
 - Git
 - Gitlab
 - Docker
 - Figma

- SCRUM
- Communication
- Team Work Critical Thinking
- Leadership

SOCIAL ACCOUNTS

 Portfolio: https://www.sandipthapa.com.np/

• LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sandipthapa99/

• Github: https://github.com/sandipthapa99/